Cody Kimbell

Phone: (713) 823-7881 | Email: codykimbell@gmail.com | Location: Lockhart, TX 78644

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/cody-kimbell/ | GitHub: https://github.com/codykimb/

Portfolio: https://codykimb.github.io/CodyKimbPortfolio/

Full-stack web developer with a certificate from The University of Texas looking to transition into software engineering and web development full-time. Record store co-owner and multifaceted self-starter with over 10 years experience in the music industry leveraging creativity and knowledge of computers and technology to create high quality experiences and products. National and international tour veteran with valuable experience working collaboratively in fast-paced high-pressure environments.

Technical Skills

- · Languages: JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, SQL
- Applications: GitHub, MySQL, NoSQL
- Tools: MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js, Bootstrap, Handlebars

Projects

NOW PLAYING

https://github.com/drewvena/now-playing/ | https://nowplayingapp.herokuapp.com/

Role: Full-stack developer, created the concept, created the models and views, wrote Javascript functions, assisted layouts and styling

Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Handlebars, Node.is, Express.is, MySQL, Sequelize

Now Playing is a music-focused social media app for sharing and discovering new music. Users can create posts, like posts and add comments. The home feed can be filtered based on different criteria such as genre, decade and format. Includes user authentication!

CINEQUIZ

https://github.com/drewvena/git-it-right/ \ https://drewvena.github.io/git-it-right/

Role: Javascript programer, quiz code functionality

Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript, OMDb API, GIPHY API

Cinequiz uses the OMDb API to gather information on films to create a quiz. Given a movie title, correct and incorrect actor choices are assembled, shuffled and displayed. The game also uses the GIPHY API to respond with gifs based on user choices. Highscores are saved, sorted and can also be updated!

Experience

CO-OWNER / VICE PRESIDENT

JANUARY 2019 - PRESENT

Bluebonnet Records (Lockart, TX)

• Started this business from scratch with one co owner. Did everything including filing as an LLC, setting up the store and displays, accounting, marketing, social media, stocking/ordering, and built a website.

• Currently manage a small team with a co-owner and 2 employees, oversee online orders, handle QuickBooks and basic acconting, price and appraise records as needed.

MUSIC TEACHER

FEBRUARY 2017 - MAY 2018

Round Rock ISD (Round Rock, TX)

- Taught K-5 music and planned a curriculum based on the RRISD guidelines with a focus on using modern instructional technologies. Managed a rotating schedule of 300+ kids and modified instructions to meet the needs of each individual child and class.
- Lead units on guitar (3-5), recorder (3-5) and keyboard (K-5) as well as extra units for 4th and 5th grade on ukelele and music technology using the Google Music Lab.

BOX OFFICE

SEPTEMBER 2014 - JUNE 2016

Austin City Limits Live at The Moody Theatre (Austin, TX)

- Worked all the way up from intern, to usher, to will call, and then box office staff. Received promotions due to computer competency and willingness to take on more responsibility.
- Responsibilities include ticket sales, will call, and providing specialized customer service such as ticket reprints, reseating, fraudulent ticket disputes, and filling in for the box office manager as needed.

MUSIC TEACHER

JUNE 2014 - FEBRUARY 2017

Opus One Music (Austin, TX)

 Taught preschool music fundamentals and planned a curriculum based on Opus One guidelines. Managed 10 different preschool accounts.

Education

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development from The University of Texas

Certificate in Business Foundations from The University of Texas

Bachelor of Arts in Music from The University of Texas

TEXES Certified (Music K-12)

Google Certified Educator